Tom Wagner

FRONT-END DEVELOPER (REACT / JAVASCRIPT)

Contact Information

Mobile: 07817251870

Email: wagner.tomek@gmail.com

Address: London, SE17





tomw.netlify.app





Education

FOUNDERS AND CODERS

Full-stack developer | 2020

- -18 week full-stack selective bootcamp with a focus on strong fundamentals (e.g. vanilla JS) and project work.
- Emphasis on pair programming and team mentality.
- TDD, agile and continuous integration tools used throughout.
- The course culminates with a 3-week project for an external product owner: see details overleaf.

UNIVERSITY OF WEST LONDON

BA(Hons) Business Studies 2.1 | 2011

Tech

FE/BE: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Airtable

TESTING: Jest, Tape, Codecov

TOOLS: Git, Travis, Heroku, Netlify

DESIGN: Figma

Professional History

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Tech For Better | May 2020 - Present

- Development of full-stack MVP application for Teach A Man To Fish charity
- Working with React, Node, Express, PostgreSQL
- Testing with Jest, Supertest
- Agile workflow, team of 4 devs

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

Freelance | June 2019 - present

- Developed and deployed a number of full-stack applications using React, Node, Express, JavaScript, jQuery, MongoDB, and PostgreSQL
- Small jobs within Wordpress, Deployment, Design, etc
- Taught myself a good level of Front-end and server technologies with a strong focus on React and Node

FOUNDER

Maria Sabina | May 2015 - June 2019

I have built, ran, and sold a small street-food restaurant. I covered all admin, finance, business development, people management/HR, marketing, and supplier management with my partner covering the remaining.

RECRUITER

Freelance | August 2013 - August 2015

- I covered areas of Technology and then Sales and Marketing
- Built a strong social media presence through LinkedIn, Twitter and Google Plus
- Managed candidates pre and post onboarding
- Built a strong understanding of corporate technology sector and some Agile practices

Profile Summary

I am a self-taught, enthusiastic, and a very passionate front-end developer recently graduated from a prominent Founders and Coders bootcamp. I have previously worked in sales and recruitment then moved onto founding of own restaurant business in South London. Finally, last year, I decided to turn my programming hobby into a full-time career.

I am an active member of FreeCodeCamp and Founders and Coders communities. I enjoy teaching and mentoring others as well as learning new tech in my spare time.

Short Courses

- Web Development Bootcamp Colt Steele Udemy
- Advanced Web Development Bootcamp Colt Steele Udemy
- Modern React Bootcamp Colt Steele Udemy
- Data Structures and Algorihtms Colt Steele Udemy
- Responsive Web Design Certification FreeCodeCamp
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Certification FreeCodeCamp
- Front End Libraries Certification FreeCodeCampAPI's and Microservices Certification FreeCodeCamp
- Learn ReactJS P1 & P2 CodeCademy

Projects

CARDLY

UI/UX Lead | May 2020

- Flashcard app made for people who like to learn using 'flashcard' technique
- One week design sprint and user testing using Figma and rapid prototyping, two one week development sprints
- I introduced Material UI and styled-components and the assured team was trained in using them by writing style guide and basic docks
- Actively participated in backend build as well as all other stages of development and was generally responsible for implementing testing and maintaining a good quality of overall code



IVE STOCK

https://github.com/fac19/Cardley

https://cardley.netlify.app/

Solo Developer | January 2020

My first full-stack web application built with aim to help small food business controling their daily stock levels, sales and wastage. Built for my own business over 1 month solo sprint. uses passport user validation, MongoDB with mongoose and Express with 'ejs'. I delivered whole project alone.

https://github.com/tacotoemeck/iVeStock



https://polar-lake-04436.herokuapp.com/

RESTFUL API - CODE SNIPPETS

Developer | January 2020

- REST API returning ISON data with endpoints for creating, reading, updating and deleting stored resources.
- Purpose of this API is to create a a database of useful and easily accessible code examples for students and developers alike.
- Project build as a part of Founders and Coders FAC19.

https://github.com/fac19/week7-CRaKT



https://crakt.herokuapp.com/